# **KASHYAP THAKKAR**

46 Terrace Dr, Hamilton, ON L9A 2Y6

Phone: 289-689-1873 | Email: kashyapthakkar1199@gmail.com | Portfolio: http://kashyapthakkar.com/

### **Summary:**

Experienced Software Engineering recent graduate with valuable programming skills and problem-solving passion. Excellent communication skills, great analytical skills and ability to work precisely in any driven environment. Self-motivated and self-learner with curiosity to develop and to learn about emerging technologies.

### **Technical Skills:**

- Programming Languages/ Technologies: Python, Java, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, PHP, Swift, C#, Ruby, jQuery, Bootstrap
- Frameworks: Node.js, React.js (Redux), Django, ASP.NET, Laravel, Codelgniter, Mustache, Vue.js
- Database: MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, MSSQL, ORACLE, SQLite
- Application Deployment: AZURE, AWS, Heroku, Docker, GoDaddy, WordPress
- Operating System: Linux, Windows, macOS
- Testing Knowledge: Blackbox and Automation testing (Katalon Recorder, JUnit, Selenium)
- **Tools**: PyCharm, MS Visual Studio, NetBeans, Eclipse, Atom, MS Office, Notepad++, Visio, MS Project 2016, VS Code, Android Studio, Katalon Automation Recorder, XCode, Jira
- Version Control Tools: Git (Bitbucket, GitHub, Gitlab)

## **Work Experience:**

Software Developer | Mohawk College, Hamilton, ON

Jan 2019 - Aug 2019

- Developed a web solution of cloud accounting portal for FlowCPA using HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, PHP, Laravel, MySQL, and other web technologies
- Worked in consultation with faculty advisors from software development Mohawk College, business analysts, business analytics, and project manager
- Built a data structure to ask customers some basic accounting questions about their business and suggest the best accounting apps according to their responses
- Worked with 3<sup>rd</sup> parties accounting apps like Xero and HUBDOC to connect their services with the client's website using their APIs
- Integrated services like jQuery calendar, Google Custom Search API, Zoom Video Conference to the website
- Assisted in developing new features and functionalities for applications as per requirements as well as in identifying and debugging issues in code

#### **Software Tester** | Ledstar Inc., Woodbridge, ON

Jan 2018 - Aug 2018

- Performed UI and Functional testing on Android and iOS devices (smartphones, tablets) using Katalon Studio
- Configured various manufactured PC boards and controllers
- Assisted in testing PC applications for bugs
- Documented test results and kept track of bugs found in the product
- Assisted senior engineers in testing dynamic message sign (DMS) controller firmware

• Took part in Writing test scripts to verify functionality

### **Technical Projects:**

Portfolio in React: April 2020

 Built a single page application as a portfolio in react which shows all my experience, education history, and projects that I have done with smooth design and transitions

- Added some interesting features like dark mode, and choosing different themes for the website
- Technologies used: ReactJS, React Router, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

#### **Technoholic – eCommerce website:**

Dec 2019

- Created a fully functional responsive eCommerce website
- Technologies used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, Bootstrap, MySQL, Katalon Studio
- https://csunix.mohawkcollege.ca/~000742712/projects/Capstone/

COCOMO Calculator: Dec 2019

- Built a COCOMO calculator in a team of software development students to estimate the level of effort needed to produce a given quantity of code
- Technologies used: ASP.NET, C#, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

#### **Payment Processing with Stripe API:**

Oct 2019

- Developed a subscription app using Stripe API that allows customer users to create and manage subscriptions and payment methods.
- Design web application frontend using Mustache, Backend using Nodejs and Express and implemented Two-factor authentication using Twilio API

#### SMS bot with FaaS and DBaaS:

Oct 2019

- Built a serverless SMS bot using Twilio, which uses a microservice (DBaaS) to store application data
- Technologies used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, WebSocket, Twilio, Redis, SQLite, GitHub API

Slackbot with YELP API: Sept 2019

- Created a Slackbot using Node.js and YELP API that delivers information about local restaurants according to commands delivered in the Slack chat window
- Technologies used: Node.js, YELP API, SQLite, Slackbots

Explore Hamilton Dec 2018

- A web application called Explore Hamilton which helps users to explore different tourist places located in Hamilton city
- Created a responsive web design to render well on small devices (i.e. Android/iPhone)
- Used Hamilton open data for this application
- Technologies used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, Bootstrap, BING maps
- https://csunix.mohawkcollege.ca/~000742712/release/

### **Education:**

Computer Systems Technology - Software Development (Co-op)

Jan 2017 - Dec 2019

Mohawk College, Hamilton, ON.

Overall GPA: 81

**LinkedIn** | https://www.linkedin.com/in/kashyapthakkar1/

**GitHub** | https://github.com/kashyapthakkar

**References** | Available upon request